healthyfiftyplus.com 2014-02-24

# Privacy Policy « Healthy Fifty Plus

This Privacy Policy explains the practices employed by HEALTHY FIFTYMedia in collecting and using your information and the ways in which you can influence these. This Privacy Policy relates to websites operated from time to time by HEALTHY FIFTYMedia.

HEALTHY FIFTY will collect various types of information about you through your use of our websites to process your requests and orders, to provide a more personalised web-surfing and shopping experience and to help us improve the services we offer. In doing this we may also collect anonymous information about you through the use of cookies. HEALTHY FIFTY  will be the Data Controller of any personal data we collect about you.

### What information do we collect about you?

Through HEALTHY FIFTY websites you can, amongst other things, order products and services, enter competitions, subscribe to our publications, vote in polls, play games, complete surveys and place postings on forums.

In order to process your requests and orders and other activities, it may be necessary to collect personally identifiable information about you. The type of personally identifiable information that may be collected includes, but is not limited to: your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, credit/debit card information. You may also be asked to provide additional (non-mandatory) pieces of information for our research purposes or choose to provide information by making a posting on a forum.

In addition, we may collect anonymous information about you and your website usage through the use of cookies. Such information will not be personally identifiable to you. If you choose, you may opt out of allowing our cookies to collect information about you. For further information please go to the section on cookies below.

Some HEALTHY FIFTY websites offer services that require you to set up an account prior to receiving such services. To create a secure account you may use your email address and a password or, if the HEALTHY FIFTY website offers a Facebook single-sign-on service, you will be able to register for and log in to your HEALTHY FIFTYwebsite account using your Facebook account.

If you choose to use the Facebook single-sign-on service we will gain access, upon your explicit consent, to your basic Facebook profile information, such as your name, profile picture and list of friends and any other information notified to you by Facebook prior to you completing the single-sign-on authorisation process.

### How will we use the information about you?

We will use the personal information you provide to us to process your orders and requests. We may also use this information to communicate with you directly, for example to notify you in the event you have won a competition or to contact you in relation to an account you hold with us.

We will use the anonymous information we collect about you to analyse web usage and compile aggregate statistics about our users. We will use this non-personally identifiable information, for advertising and marketing purposes and to enable us to provide a more personalised internet experience. For further information please go to the section on cookies below.

### Marketing

From time to time we will ask you whether you wish to receive marketing material from HEALTHY FIFTYMedia containing information about our products and services. If you do not wish to receive such information please ensure that you opt-in or opt-out of receiving such information as appropriate. If you have consented to receiving such material you may opt-out at a later stage from:

  * Emails – by clicking on an email unsubscribe link;
  * SMS – by following the instructions in any SMS message      received;
  * Post or telemarketing – by writing to The Head of      Database Marketing at HEALTHY FIFTY, Blue Fin Building, 110      Southwark Street, London SE1 0SU.

Upon registration for competitions or other online services you may, in some cases, be automatically opted-in to receive e-mail marketing, newsletters or partner promotions containing material. If this is the case you may unsubscribe to receiving such marketing material at any time by clicking on the e-mail unsubscribe link.

### What will we disclose to third parties?

If you consent we may sell, rent or trade your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes. Such third parties will be carefully selected and registered with the Information Commissioner.

We may also pass your personal information to third parties to enable them to process a request, order or service; or to supply you with a prize in the event you win a competition or in order to obtain professional advice.

We may provide anonymous, non-personally identifiable aggregate information to advertisers and our business partners, including information relating to sales and web-usage, to enable us to sell advertising and monitor the efficacy of our business partnerships. We may also pass such statistical information onto reputable third parties for onward sale.

It is possible that HEALTHY FIFTYMedia could merge or be acquired by another business. If this happens we may share the information that relates to you. You will be sent notice of such an event.

HEALTHY FIFTYMedia reserves the right to disclose personally identifiable information in order to comply with the law, applicable regulations and government requests. We also reserve the right to use such information in order to protect our operating systems and integrity as well as other users.

Any third parties employed by us to process your data on our behalf are subject to contractual obligations to protect the security of your data in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

### How do we protect your information?

Once we have received your data we will ensure that it is treated with the utmost respect and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and any applicable regulations. Your data will be stored on our secure server within the UK. We follow strict security procedures in order that the data we collect is stored and disclosed appropriately and securely.

Unfortunately the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although HEALTHY FIFTYMedia will do its best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk.

### Other Websites

Please note that clicking on links and advertisements on our websites may result in your transferral to another website, where data privacy practices may vary to that of HEALTHY FIFTYMedia’s. If transferred to another site you should consult their privacy policy as we are not responsible for and have no control over information that is submitted to or collected by these third parties.

### Changes to our privacy policy

HEALTHY FIFTYMedia keeps this privacy policy under review and may update it at any time. Any updates will be made on this page so that you can always find out what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we will disclose it.

### How to contact us

If you have any queries relating to the HEALTHY FIFTYMedia Privacy Policy please contact us by writing to The Head of Database Marketing, HEALTHY FIFTY, 98 Southwark Street, London SE1 0SU

COOKIES

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small text file that we, and in certain circumstances third parties, place on your browser when you visit our websites or open some of our emails.  
Cookies, amongst other things, allow HEALTHY FIFTY to recognise you each time you re-visit one of our websites and provide you with a more personalised user experience. There are in existence a variety of different cookies which are designed for use in specific sets of circumstances.

### How do we and third parties use cookies?

You should be aware that information on you may be collected through the use of cookies when you use HEALTHY FIFTYMedia websites and/or selected third party sites. It is essential that we use some cookies in order to provide you with the services you have requested from us. Some cookies, however, whilst useful, are not essential, and when using HEALTHY FIFTY websites you agree to the use of these non-essential cookies unless you specifically set your browser to reject them. Please see ‘How to manage or refuse cookies’ below for further details.

When you initially enter one of our sites we may place an anonymous cookie on your browser to enable us to recognise you the next time you visit the website. We may also place a further cookie on your browser when you register for one of our services, this will enable us to remember you next time you come to sign in, eliminating the need for you to re-enter your login details and customising your future uses of our sites.

Cookies may also be used to track your use of HEALTHY FIFTYMedia websites to better develop them, for example, determining which parts of the websites are more popular and determining content accordingly.

We may also place cookies on your browser to provide you with behavioural advertising and monitor the advertising on our sites to, amongst other things, ensure that you are not subjected to intrusive advertising.

Small pieces of code called pixel tags, web beacons or GIF files, are used in conjunction with cookies to help us manage and monitor our online advertising and wider business arrangements with third parties. These files will allow us to aggregate anonymous information relating to advertising and website usage. The type of information collected includes, but is not limited to, information relating to advertising responses, page views, promotion views and purchases made. Such pixel tags may be used to recognise third party cookies (cookies generated by third parties) and inform us and/or third parties of which advertisement or link brought you to our website, allowing us to monitor the efficacy of our business relationships with third parties. Please see the section below entitled ‘Use of different cookies’ for more detail on the various cookies in use by HEALTHY FIFTYMedia and how they work.

### How to manage or refuse cookies

If you do not want your browser to accept cookies and use them in the ways described above it is possible to change your browser settings. It is also possible to delete existing cookies from your browser. However blocking all cookies will affect your web experience and may result in some parts of HEALTHY FIFTY websites not functioning properly. Some cookies are designed to help save you time, for example, by remembering your contact details when you are making an order for the second time â€” this means that you will not have to complete the contact section again unless your details have changed. The procedure for modifying your privacy preferences is different for each internet browser and we recommend you visit the following websites for further information on altering your cookie settings:

For more detailed information on how to clear or disable all of your browser cookies, please go to [http://www.google.com/support/accounts/bin/answer.py?answer=32050&hl=en](http://www.google.com/support/accounts/bin/answer.py?answer=32050&hl=en)

### Use of different cookies

We will use different cookies at various different stages of your use of our websites.

### Tracking and Customisation Cookies

These are used to recognise repeat visitors to HEALTHY FIFTY websites and customise the visitor experience, as described above. They may also be used in conjunction with other information we or our third party partners hold to attempt to record specific browsing information (for example, regarding the way visitors arrive at HEALTHY FIFTYMedia websites, pages viewed, options selected, information entered and the path taken through the HEALTHY FIFTYMedia websites).

### Session Cookie

These are used to maintain your session when you sign in on HEALTHY FIFTY websites, allowing you to access HEALTHY FIFTY online services without the need to sign in on every page you visit. The session cookie is used to tailor advertising to you on HEALTHY FIFTY online services and websites and selected third party websites. If you opt out of tailored advertising, we stop using this cookie for this purpose.

### Survey and Exposure Cookie

This is provided by Survey Interactive for HEALTHY FIFTY website survey purposes. Storing this cookie allows the accurate measurement of advertising on HEALTHY FIFTY websites, should you subsequently choose to participate in an advertisement effectiveness survey. If you do not choose to participate in an advertisement effectiveness survey, this cookie will expire without being used.

### Advertising Cookies

In addition HEALTHY FIFTYMedia works with third parties for the purpose of delivering targeted behavioural advertising to the HEALTHY FIFTY websites. Through the use of cookies, anonymous information about your use of our websites and other websites will be used to provide more relevant adverts about goods and services of interest to you. Specific cookies used by HEALTHY FIFTYMedia in relation to behavioural advertising include:

**Audience   Science** | The cookie enables behavioural advertising. Audience Science is Healthy Fifty partner for providing this service and provides   behavioural advertising through the use of “audience segments”.   Cookies are used by Audience Science to provide you with advertising based on   content that you have previously viewed on HEALTHY FIFTY websites   and other third party websites. If you do not wish to receive this behavioural   advertising you may opt-out at <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices>   . We may also share behavioural data with other websites. This may mean that   when you are on other websites you are served advertising based on your   behaviour at HEALTHY FIFTYwebsites and on HEALTHY FIFTYwebsites you may be served advertising based on your behaviour on other   sites. Please visit audiencescience.com/privacy.asp to view the privacy policy   of Audience Science. 

For more information on online behavioural advertising and about how to   turn this feature off, please visit <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/opt-out>.

Opting out ‘opt-out’ cookie to your device. Please note that if you   subsequently delete all of your cookies you will also delete the Audience   Science opt-out cookie.  
  
---|---  
**Adtech** | Adtech serves advertising to HEALTHY FIFTY websites. When an   advertisement is requested by a website, Adtech receives information from   your browser which influences the type of advertisement displayed. To opt-out   of Adtech using this cookie data please visit http://www.adtech.com/cookie_opt-out/.   When you opt out, Adtech will send an ‘opt-out’ cookie to your device. Please   note that if you subsequently delete all of your cookies, you will also   delete this opt-out cookie.  
  
Opting out of behavioural advertising or adtech tracking does not mean that you will no longer receive advertising when you are using HEALTHY FIFTY websites. It simply means the advertising you see will not be customised for you.

More general information about behavioural advertising can be found at [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.ipcmedia.com/www.youronlinechoices.com).

### Research Cookies

**Nielsen** | Nielsen is a measurement and research company that gathers   data across HEALTHY FIFTYwebsites through using cookies and pixel   tags for the purposes of gathering research data on the traffic and users   across HEALTHY FIFTYMedia websites. To find out how Nielsen use   the information collected and how to opt out please visit <http://www.nielsen-online.com/privacy.jsp?section=leg_scs>  
---|---  
  
### Cookies placed independently by third parties

The majority of adverts you see on HEALTHY FIFTY websites will have been placed by third parties. These third parties may choose to generate their own cookies for the purposes of collecting anonymous information relating to the viewing of their advertising. The information collected cannot be used to personally identify someone.
